Good evening, students and teachers online.
I am Ji Yang, a professional teacher in the field of clothing and clothing at Dalian University.
Thank you very much for the forum organized by our Colour company.
I am very happy to be able to share and communicate with you some of my experiences in teaching.
This time, the topic is Digital Virtual Design to Help Clothing Design Teaching Transformation and Upgrading.
It is mainly divided into three parts.
The first part is to introduce our professional digitalization development process.
The second part is to introduce the application and some results of digital virtual design in teaching.
The third part is to discuss clothing design teaching transformation and upgrade.
In the introduction,
I would like to talk about the background of our school.
Our school was established in 1985 as a clothing school.
It is also the first clothing major in the country.
In 2013, it was the first comprehensive four-point major in the country.
There is also a national experimental teaching demonstration center.
In 2014,
I got a master's degree
in teaching results.
In 2015,
I got the virtual virtual experimental teaching center in Liangning Province.
In 2019,
I was the first first-class construction major in the country.
Our school now has four directions.
Clothing and clothing design,
clothing design and engineering,
performance,
and the digital media technology major that was just established in 2022.
Our major is digitalized clothing design teaching.
It has been in development for nearly 20 years.
Before 2009,
digital teaching has been gradually transformed from traditional teaching to multimedia teaching.
Using digital images such as Photoshop and Kodak,
software for clothing design and teaching.
Since 2009,
our school has introduced
the clothing computer support design,
which is the clothing system.
In this way,
digital teaching has been upgraded.
At that time,
the software we cooperated with was AGM,
AGM-S.
When I was in teaching,
it was the first time I came into contact with virtual sewing technology.
But the virtual sewing at that time
was still very simple.
It is very advanced.
It is a software that can provide a very simple and practical design.
For example,
there is a design that is similar to the design of a clothing model in Sichuan.
Then it can achieve the effect of virtual sewing and then Sichuan.
From 2012,
our school introduced the Cloud 3D software.
At that time,
it seemed to be more than 3.
This version is the software.
It is much more mature than the one I have seen before.
Our school just started using this.
When it comes to digitalization and virtualization, some of the professors and instructors have already learned about the future of digitalization and virtualization clothing design.
They have started to conduct research on the subject of digitalization of clothing.
Some professors and students have conducted experiments on clothing engineering, virtual testing, fabric testing, and pressure testing.
In 2016, some of the professors and students have completed the virtualization of their own works.
At that time, the results were very technological and avant-garde.
Later, some professors and students have started to introduce digital virtualization design into the scientific research project.
Generally, some professors and students have been engaged in traditional design.
Some professors and students have been engaged in traditional clothing restoration, sports clothing, and some professional clothing.
In 2016, when the training project was set up, our school wanted to apply digitalized virtual technology to the teaching of this course.
In 2018, the third grade of the women's clothing line, the third grade of the 16th grade students, started the virtual three-dimensional three-dimensional design class.
At the same time,
we have also used this technology in the education reform of structural and engineering such as digitalization.
I remember that at that time, the software of Clore has reached version 5.0.
The equipment and setting requirements of the computer are very high.
Previously, the computer of our computer could not support it.
Then our school also specially spent a lot of money to build a digital virtual computer.
We have also built a digital virtual computer lab to meet the requirements of our teaching and research.
In 2018, we also passed the preparation of the first batch of virtual
anti-theft teaching experiment, the national first-class course.
In the later period, we also took a few courses in this virtual anti-theft teaching.
In order to achieve the quality of teaching quality,
and during the epidemic,
this kind of digitalized virtual teaching,
and this kind of virtual anti-theft experimental platform,
this kind of model,
is the advantage.
Then it also promotes our digitalization.
The digitalization of education reform is such a step.
In 2001, we gradually have some of this kind of cultivation results.
That is, in 2021,
our school began to prepare for the virtual exhibition of graduates.
Then in the second year, the college student fashion week was successfully released in 2022.
I also participated in some competitions.
There is also this school-level cooperation project.
The second part is the application of digital virtual design in education.
So why do we talk about this virtual design technology
and introduce it to the fashion design profession?
In the last episode of this guest,
and other teachers are sharing,
you talked a lot.
Then I will not explain too much in this.
The main thing is that the first one is the trend for industry development.
That is, the fashion company is to promote the development of the fashion industry,
or the green industry.
In short, the fashion digital virtual design of the fashion industry is that they first transform.
Then our school will cultivate such talents to adapt to the development of this industry.
The second is virtual design.
It has the potential to improve design efficiency and accuracy.
The third is to strengthen the ability of practical control.
The fourth is to cultivate the comprehensive ability of the science and technology department.
Then the student can have more possibilities of design like this.
The fifth is to promote the innovation of teaching methods.
Because there is such a thing,
for our current young people,
students prefer this kind of virtual digitalization,
and can have interactive,
this kind of fun,
this kind of course,
to stimulate students' interest in this kind of learning,
as well as positivity.
Then I am,
Mr. Ren is in his software course,
there are a lot of this kind of experience sharing.
Then I am in the whole,
I,
I teach this kind of course.
Then,
there is such a course system of a construction.
The main thing is the digital virtual design practice.
The teaching is divided into four parts.
The first one is the virtual imitation experiment.
There are a total of five classes in this.
In this kind of virtual imitation class,
it is able to give you a question like this,
provide a virtual imitation,
a virtual imitation of a thought,
and increase the interaction of students.
It also helps students to change the structure of this kind of three-dimensional and two-dimensional clothing.
The second one is the second stage,
which is in this third grade.
We open the digital technology of this kind of course,
that is, software,
clothing,
and this three-dimensional virtual design.
Three-dimensional,
in this class,
it is the operating software of the classroom.
With such a technology,
it can be in the back of the big class,
in this kind of big class in the third grade,
it starts to carry out the practice of the homework in this class,
or the practice of the big homework.
Then at a higher level,
it is this kind of practical course,
like design internship,
comprehensive design,
including design,
all of them can carry out this kind of virtual design.
This kind of support is also good,
and then there is also a line-up.
In this way,
there is such an application.
That is,
I have gone through these few classes,
and then I will share with you how I use this.
These two are open first.
Like this one on the left,
this one,
is the intelligent suit customized.
It is the intelligent suit customized that we applied for in 2018.
Then this is mainly
a virtual RFI
in the field of factory urbanization
of Dalian Dayang Fashion Group.
Then I is this class,
this experimental system is quite big.
I took a part of it.
This experiment,
it is a sense of reality
that can make students have this kind of magical
and practical interaction.
实验呢,分为虚拟工厂,体型智能评价,工艺准备,材料准备,裁剪,缝纫,多个这种实验的这种模块。
那像这个虚拟仿真实验里面呢,我们会上服装设备认知与实践这门课,还有这个生产管理。
这样的话,就是免去了我们总是要带学生到服装工厂去参观的这样一个问题。
那学生呢,可以就是反复在这个虚拟仿真实验里面呢,学习和认知。
这里面呢,有一套就是非常完整的西装制作的流程。
有虚拟,有知识点,然后有理论,还有那工厂这个实际操作的视频。
所以在南庄酒馆,
也是可以利用这个实验进行实践教学的。
右边呢,这个是基于女装原型三维立体服装设计产品的这个虚拟仿真虚拟实验。
这个实验的包含女装原型与人体认知,女装原型虚拟结构认知,女装结构的结构与重构。
还有虚拟场合,这种虚拟仿真设计,四个学习模块。
现在上这门课呢,主要是服装结构与工艺,还有成衣结构与工艺,这两门课。
同学们呢,可以通过这门课的学习呢,讲服装的结构原理,进行虚拟化,然后交互的这个学习。
加强学生对服装结构,服装版型的这样的一个理解。
时间远延,我们不多看了。
有这个感兴趣的同学和老师,可以到我们官方的网站搜索。
可以到我们国家虚拟仿真实验教学平台,收到这两门课。
可以进行这个实验学习。
这个是三维虚拟立体设计。
就是在三年级开设的这个二十四课时的这个可漏软件的这个基础使用方法。
那这里面呢,也是像我们在老师培训的时候这个初级课程。
主要是以替虚拟。
衬衫,裤子,卫衣,这样基础款式。
通过这些案例,然后呢,教授这种软件的各个这个操作方法。
也把这个基本的一般简单的这种色彩呀,图案,还有面料设计,包括调整属性,也是在这门课里面去教授。
有了这个一定的这个技术的虚拟技术的支持。
学生会了。
会了以后呢,我们也是在这学期,紧接着会开设女装结构设计与工艺这门课。
这门课呢,是主要理论部分呢,是讲授的是创新结构设计。
作业的设置呢,是以学生为中心。
这种实践教学体系。
然后启发和引导学生呢,去找一些当下流行的这种服装的图片。
然后呢,进行分析它的结构特点。
在进行这个创新结构的这个设计。
一般我们分组,两三个人一组。
针对这个创新这个结构的理论,美解课的课程理论。
然后呢,同学们在进行模拟的这种结构设计的这个研究。
再做出来样衣。
那以前呢,同学呢,就是要通过这个纸样也好,立材也好,一遍遍的实践。
然后呢,出现问题,做不出来那个效果,它就要重做。
这时呢,就会费时费势。
然后同学们的那个压力也挺大。
从这个女装方向同学开始学会了,开始上这个Cloud3D这个课以后呢。
我就鼓励他们尝试用Cloud软件进行这个辅助的结构设计。
我说你可以就是先根据款式呢,咱们进行这个结构设计。
然后呢,就是你可以先平面或者先立材。
然后把我们的这个版型变成数字版型。
在虚拟缝合。
虚拟缝合看有问题了。
然后我们在Cloud里面进行调版。
调到Cloud里面没有问题了。
虚拟展示没有问题了。
就可以。
然后再去做出来实物。
然后我们再对比效果。
也有呢,同学在这个设计过程当中呢。
就是完全是立材的这个出来的。
然后把这个立材的样板呢再变成这种数字样板。
然后用Cloud呢去模拟。
把它这个加一些面料属性啊图案呢。
然后再对比效果。
这个学生呢就是在这个过程中呢。
他又可以去加强这个样板的这训练。
他又这个提高了质疑的这种效率。
然后同时他Cloud的这个操作的熟练性也提高。
这作业呢是分组进行的。
他们呢在作业做完以后呢。
要进行一个PPT的一个分享。
分组讨论。
研究分析他们的这个模拟的这个款式。
在制作过程中有什么问题。
有什么解决方式。
在后边的几届呢同学。
用虚拟展示的虚拟试穿同学越来越多了。
有的同学呢还有很多更有趣的这种尝试。
同学们的这个学习积极性啊都有所提高。
还加强了他们实践训练与团队合作的这样的一个能力。
这是一个也是在大三接着女装姐夫设计的一门课。
那这个是一个实践课程。
两周的实践课程。
以前呢是。
是可以跟企业我们做一些项目的训练。
从去年开始呢。
我们的也是系主任说。
想去做做一些虚拟设计的提高的这样是训练。
就在这门课里面呢。
我们把这门课就给到我。
在这里面呢我们就是让学生呢开始进行这个。
更多的这个虚拟的这个技能的提高。
因为有的同学吧。
他做的服装的很多是开始用力才去做。
所以呢我们学院呢。
在前应该是两年前。
进了一个这个PGPMG的这个样板扫描仪。
那在这门课呢。
刚开始上课时候呢。
就先把这个扫描仪的这个使用方式。
然后怎么把这个镜的白皮布的镜板。
然后扫到这个扫描以后呢。
变成数字版型。
有了这样的一个数字版型。
同学们就开始进行这个。
一种比较细腻的。
这种的比如说面料质感呢。
附件细节呀。
还有这个渲染效果啊。
模特的这个皮肤啊。
然后包括场景啊。
怎么去这个在虚拟里面怎么操作。
同学呢也是通过线上。
线上的我们是录的课。
这样同学们可以随时去学习。
使同学呢更灵活的掌握了。
这种服装虚拟缝合技术。
能够完成他们的这个。
综合的服装设计的这样的一个。
创新的结构设计。
像这种啊。
也是以水元素。
为灵感的这种概念性服装。
如果我们做出。
直接像传统的做这种。
很难达成。
但在虚拟设计里面就可以去。
可以去无限的去想象。
去实践它。
所以同学们呢还是挺愿意去。
用这种虚拟设计的方法。
去这个做实践。
那最后呢这个班呢。
把我们的这个。
两周的实践的成果。
做了一个这个虚拟秀。
我是截取了一部分。
截取了一部分同学。
在这些同学的这个作品里面。
不是所有都能达到动态走秀的这种水准。
那么同学们呢也会用场景。
或者是后期制作的这种方法。
加上这个动感。
然后编辑一个这个比较。
对于他们作为一个结构秀来说。
还是可以的。
这个效果。
嗯。
I made a weekly video for them to watch.
Let's watch it quickly.
This is a video of a student participating in the skating competition.
It also has a virtual effect.
This kind of large clothing is not very stable.
It is difficult to achieve the effect of walking in a short period of time.
So I told the student to record a video of the rotation.
Later, we can add some movement to the effect of the production.
This is the creation of the water element at the end.
I changed it to a more flexible fabric.
This is a course for students.
This course is about fashion design innovation research and practice.
It is a general course.
It is divided into two stages.
There are a total of 160 courses.
It is a course of the second year.
The main course is a series of courses on new water designers, design planning, creative design, and product practice.
It also encourages everyone to use virtual design to do design assistance.
Because it is a research subject, it is available all over the country.
So the software they are using is not only using Cloud 3D.
Many students use other virtual design software.
When designing, it is also like some conceptual clothing.
They can have a better design concept representation and effect in this virtual environment.
This student is doing a swimsuit.
Because they are under the guidance of the instructor.
The entire subject group actually did a show.
Then they do swimsuits.
When they do swimsuits, the layout is very simple.
But they make adjustments in the shell.
After adjustment, it is mainly for this kind of positioning digital printing.
In this software, in our shell software, digital printing is used again.
The effect is particularly good.
It is more precise and realistic.
Next is the graduate design of this department.
It is in 2021.
Our school has been preparing for half a year.
Selected this 13 sets of dynamic 26 sets of static.
In our это, at that time, the program was still in university.
We want to launch our virtual fashion show in this college student fashion week.
The theme is virtual coexist.
We go to the college student fashion week every year.
But due to the epidemic, the school can not make a display in Beijing for two consecutive years.
Our school can not reach the Beijing scene.
So it was only in the school's performance hall that the video of the live show was recorded, and then it was released in the University of Shenzhen.
In 2021, because the pandemic was also known as the year of the universe,
the international clothing industry first adopted digitalization to do virtual fashion shows and digital fashion exhibitions.
So our Dean Ding, Dean Ding Wei, decided to hold a virtual conference for our graduate students this year.
At that time, it was because only the women's direction was open for virtual classes, so we immediately began to focus on the real men's fashion.
Then the students of the fourth grade conducted a virtual conference.
We conducted a short-term training,
and then Colov Dpow conducted a training for teachers and classmates at our school.
It was the content of the emphasis we used later in our design internship.
Our teacher organized a graduation event to start clothing and modeling in their own work.
We chose five or six to design ten virtual works.
At that time, we were also working on various digital designs.
I just want to do this kind of dynamic show effect
Then Mr. Zhang reminded us that if you want to do this kind of large online release
Just do it very exquisitely
There can't be any problem
There is no problem to reach the level of this release
So in the end we chose 13 sets of dynamic
Then 26 sets are high-definition
But the effect of the students is not very perfect
I remember Tina Wang Haixia, a technical staff member of Clover
Helped us with these three sets, one by one, to change the original file
And then recorded this rendering show
In the later period, there was also Chen Gong to help us synthesize the video
At that time, the team of Clover was in Shanghai
Dean Ding led the team of our school in Dalian
Often have online meetings at night
Discuss the arrangement of the video
There is also a video editing program
Sometimes it can be turned on at more than 10 o'clock
In total, four months of historical history
Completed this virtual show
This college fashion week was the tenth anniversary of last year
They want to open offline, but have not been opened yet
Then it can't be done until July
Can only be held online
I remember the virtual show of our school at that time
There are few
Wearing gloves
It's still quite comfortable
I will wear gloves
Put an apron on
Wearing gloves
Not very comfortable
I hope to have a different feeling
Let's get rid of this
I dare to say
I think I will stay
You can find out on the Internet
I want to see what she sees
In Shenzhen, it is normal to start this kind of offline show release.
Then our school also went to Beijing to participate in this exhibition.
Then this time the theme is called the activation of traditional technology.
The promotional film made at that time and the invitation letter were all made of this kind of virtual design.
Then this time, we are professional design teachers who guide students to do virtual design and then costume design.
The post-production is done by our newly established digital technology teachers.
They use Zandimax, Blender, and other software and then use them alternately.
In the end, the final result is this kind of post-production video effect.
At that time, we still...
Well...
There is one that wants to achieve a virtual common show effect on the spot.
Then made a background.
This time, this is also done by the teacher of this digital media.
This is recorded on the spot.
Because the background is brighter on the spot.
The background may be a little bit...
In this way, we can also see its virtual.
This kind of virtual.
The effect of the virtual coming out together.
It's better to see it on the spot.
It's more shocking.
Because in the course of this department and the students,
We are involved in and involved in a lot of this kind of virtual design teaching.
So, these two years, students have participated in a lot of this kind of digital-related competitions.
Such as the Dachuan project, the challenge cup, and the future designer competition.
There are also a lot of awards.
Here, I mainly want to say that last year,
Our school organization participated in the first Zeta Cloud Cup.
China's original universe clothing design competition.
Many students have voted.
I remember that at least 12 students entered the three tracks.
Finally, it's...
Oh, this little word.
Lai Yuxin won the gold medal of this leisure sports group.
Chen Lin won the award of the creative suit and play group.
This is their virtual effect.
Finally, the third part.
Let's talk about clothing design teaching transformation upgrade.
When it comes to transformation upgrade,
It's about introducing virtual technology.
And then the virtual needle test.
And then improve our teaching quality and effect.
And then it's about improving the teacher's numbers.
Our teachers, through a lot of training,
And this lecture forum.
Improve our digital education awareness.
Improve the ability of teaching.
Students are strengthening students' practical education.
In this way, it is mainly to train them.
Such a creative thinking and creativity.
In the course setting.
It is a multiple adjustment of the training program.
According to the needs and development trends of the industry.
Improve the course setting.
Like here,
Maybe some teachers are also participating in the new 2024 training program.
Whether it is a private school or a graduate student.
They have made a lot of adjustments.
For example, our school.
This is the 2024 training program this year.
It is more focused on market demand.
Add digital fashion design research direction.
Design as the core.
Integrate art and science.
Face the new industry.
The development needs of new technologies and new positions.
Cultivate multi-dimensional cross-integrated digitalization.
Appliance talent.
The development of digital design.
In the development of our entire education upgrade.
I think it can be divided into three parts.
The first is the combination of design and technology.
That is, we can currently.
Through digital virtual design.
Through three-dimensional modeling.
Virtual reality and other technologies.
Create a flexible design environment for students.
There is also.
We are going down now.
To study the integration of technology.
Digital virtual design.
Promote this kind of.
Design and technology.
This kind of deep integration.
For example, 3D printing.
Intelligent wear.
Human engineering.
This kind of cooperation model.
Not only broadened the boundaries of design.
Also for designers.
Provide more.
This design inspiration source.
There is also.
What we are talking about now.
The collision of design and intelligence.
Then this intelligence.
Intellectualization.
Artificial intelligence.
Is a topic that we can't avoid.
Big data.
Internet of Things.
And so on.
Is for our clothing design.
Bring a new possibility.
Intellectual technology.
It can also help our designers.
Improve design efficiency and quality.
Realize the intelligent and automatic design.
Then we.
Is.
Don't do this.
To this intelligence.
Artificial intelligence.
Have a sense of fear.
In fact.
I'm thinking.
We can.
Just like us.
This kind of virtual technology.
Use so well.
That's the same.
Can make artificial intelligence.
For our virtual technology.
And this kind of.
Teaching.
Design teaching.
To integrate.
Then upgrade.
For our.
This clothing design.
In the future.
Bring a higher.
This kind of.
Level.
Transformation upgrade.
Finally.
Let our.
School.
Two.
Exhibition.
This kind of.
This.
The theme of the show.
Virtual coalescence.
Activate the future.
End of my.
Today's.
Share.
Thank you all.